RUI OLIVEIRA

INDUSTRIAL ELECTRICIAN

Male | 19/12/1995 | Portuguese 2960 Brecht, Belgium

www.rui-oliveira.com hire@rui-oliveira.com +32474127175

Profile

As an electrical professional, I have developed a diverse range of skills and expertise that would make me a valuable addition to any team. With a passion for electrical engineering and a commitment to staying up-to-date with the latest technologies, I am confident in my ability to tackle any challenge.

Experience

Vestas in Belgium Field Service Technician (Electrical / Mechanical) May 2023 - Present Full-time

AGP eGlass in Evergem, Belgium Industrial Electrician

Mar 2023 - May 2023 Full-time

 $Glass\ Processing\ Lines,\ Troubleshooting\ machinery\ problems\ electrical\ and\ mechanical,\ PLC+Robotic\ arms$

SOCEA nv in Oelegem, Belgium Industrial Electrician

May 2019 - Mar 2023 Full-time

Troubleshooting machinery problems, installing cable ducts, passing cables, connecting electrical boards, and replacing basic mechanical parts.

MEDREPAIR in Beveren, Belgium Cold technician

July 2018 - May 2019 Full-time

Repairing and maintaining refrigerated containers, performing "PTI" inspections, welding copper, and replacing motors and sensors.

SERSAN in Lourosa, Portugal Industrial Electrician

Feb 2015 - July 2018 Full-time

Repairing industrial machines (electrical and electromechanical), elaboration and electrification of electrical boards, electrical assembly of machines and structures of transport of cork and beginner of programming and automation of PLC (OMRON).

Electro Oliveira in Milheirós de Poiares, Portugal Electronic, automation and maintenance (1500 hours)

2012 - 2015 Internship

Repairing and maintaining household appliances.

Education

20221 - VP LS + HS (NEN 3140 + 3840) Aestimavi in Zwolle, Nederland	14 Mar 2024 - 1 July 2024	
Slinger Signaller (GWO) Normec ISEC in Beveren, Belgium	7 Sept 2023 - 8 Sept 2023	
Basic Technical - Mechanical RelyOn Nutec in Amsterdam, Nederland	19 June 2023 - 22 June 2023	
Basic Technical - Hydraulic RelyOn Nutec in Amsterdam, Nederland	19 June 2023 - 22 June 2023	
Basic Technical - Electrical RelyOn Nutec in Amsterdam, Nederland	19 June 2023 - 22 June 2023	
VOL-VCA PBNA in Bergen op Zoom, Netherlands	17 May 2023	
BA4 Vestas in Arnhem, Netherlands	11 May 2023 - 12 May 2023	
First Aid - Fire Awareness - Working at Heights - Manual Handling (GWO) RelyOn Nutec in Amsterdam, Nederland	8 May 2023 - 10 May 2023	
Driving course of electric forklifts, combustion and gas Cincork in Santa Maria de Lamas, Portugal	7 Mar 2018 - 3 May 2018	
Electronic, automation and maintenance +1500 hours InternshipElectronic CFPIC in São João da Madeira, Portugal	2012 - 16 Jan 2015	
Driving license AM / B / B1 Boavista in Santa Maria da Feira, Portugal	4 Dec 2015	
High School, Course of Sciences and Technologies Santa Maria da Feira in Santa Maria da Feira, Portugal	2010 - 2012	

My house is powered by a Raspberry Pi 4 and is automated using Home Assistant. With this setup, I have the ability to control various aspects such as lights, sensors, and robots, both internally (without an internet connection) and externally (via VPN "Tailscale" and IP masked by "Duck DNS").

Website 11 Feb 2022 - Present

This website was created with the aim of promoting information about my professional career, in a way that is accessible to companies and interested people. The purpose of this website is to showcase my professional career and make information easily accessible to companies and individuals who are interested in learning more about me.

Skills

Designing and analyzing systems

Experience in designing electrical systems for a variety of applications, with proficiency in software tools such as Visio and AutoCAD to analyze and optimize these systems.

Testing and Inspection

Background in testing and inspecting electrical systems to ensure compliance and functionality, with the ability to provide detailed reports on findings.

Safety and compliance

High focus on safety and compliance in all aspects of electrical work.

Troubleshooting and problem-solving

Strong analytical skills to quickly identify issues with electrical systems and develop effective solutions to resolve them.

Project management

Successful management of numerous electrical projects from start to finish, delivering high-quality results within budget and on time.

Communication and collaboration

Excellent communication and collaboration skills, enabling successful outcomes through teamwork.

Production C2

B2

C1

A2

Languages

GE UN	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING	
Listeni	ng Readir	ng Interac	tion P	
C2	C2	C2		
B2	B2	B2		
C1	C1	C1		
A2	A2	A2		
	Listeni C2 B2 C1	Listening Readin C2 C2 B2 B2 C1 C1	Listening Reading Interact C2 C2 C2 B2 B2 B2 C1 C1 C1	

Levels: A1/2: Basic - B1/2: Independent - C1/2 Proficient Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Other

Off We Go - IB&C WEEKS

17 May 2014 - 25 May 2014

Scholar Exchange experience.

Europe tour

7 Feb 2021 - Present

WRITING

C2

B1

B1

A2

Countries I visited.